所以在过去的几个视频中，我们已经了解了很多关于我们的包管理器以及它是如何工作的。
So in the last few videos we've been learning a whole lot about our package manager and how it works.
我们了解了现金和它的用途，我们已经了解了如何更新现金和如何
And we learned about the cash and what it's for we've learned about how to update the cash and how to
使用包管理器将我们系统上的所有软件升级到最新版本
upgrade all of the software on our system to the newest versions using the package manager which is
都是超级棒的东西。
all super awesome stuff.
但是我们怎么才能安装新的软件包呢？
But how can we install new packages.
这就是我们想知道的。
That's what we want to know.
根据您从前面的视频中获得的背景知识，安装将会非常简单
Well with the background that you've gained from the previous videos install it will be really easy
去理解，而不仅仅是一些你必须记住的东西。
to understand and not just something that you have to memorize.
在本视频结束时，您将了解如何从命令行安装新软件。
And by the end of this video you will know how to install new software from the command line.
因此，让我们继续并直接投入其中。
So let's go ahead and jump right into it.
好的。
OK.
因此，无论我们是否知道我们的现金和系统都是最新的，让我们继续安装一些新的
So whether we know that our cash and system are fully up to date let's go ahead and install some new
软件。
software.
比方说，我听说过一个叫“X眼”的程序，显然X总是用
So let's say that I've heard of a program called X eyes and X always apparently makes a window with
一些有趣的眼睛会随着鼠标光标在屏幕上弹出来。
some funny eyes pop up that follow your mouse cursor around the screen.
我认为这很有趣，我想安装它。
And I think this is interesting and I want to install it.
要做到这一点，首先我们需要知道消费税程序包含在什么包中。
So do that first we need to know what package the excise program comes in.
那么让我们在缓存中搜索它，我们这样做的方式是，我们执行apt缓存搜索，以查找Exex和它
So let's search the cache for it the way that we do that is we do apt cache search for excise and it
会给我们所有和消费税有关的包裹。
will give us every package that has something to do with excise.
我们听说过这个叫做x11应用程序的软件包，比方说，我们喜欢啊，这就是我听说过的
And we've heard of this package called x 11 apps let's say and we like ah that's the one I've heard
让我去仔细看看吧。
of let me go and have a closer look at it.
所以我们做apt Cash show x11个应用程序。
So we do we do apt Cash show x 11 apps.
好的。
OK.
所以你在这里给它提供包裹的名称，这会给我们一堆信息。
So you give it the name of the package here and that will give us a bunch of information.
不过，让我们把屏幕清理干净，通过更少的管道，这样我们就能更仔细地看一看。
But let's just clear the screen and pipe that through less so we get a bit of a closer look.
好的。
OK.
当我们在这里打开这个的时候，我们可以看到，实际上我们得到了很多关于这个包的信息。
And when we open this here we can see that actually that we get a lot of information about the package.
但是在下面的描述中，它说这个包裹提供了各种X
But down here in the description it says that this package provides a miscellaneous assortment of X
X Window System附带的应用程序，包括，它会告诉我们，我们有一些东西
applications that ship with the X Window System including And it will tell us that we've got something
用于操作位图图像的工具可以告诉您何时有新的电子邮件和
tools for manipulating bitmap images something for a tool that tells you when you have new e-mail and
等等。
so on.
这里有一个叫“X眼”的项目，附加活动是一个演示程序，在这个项目中，一双眼睛跟踪
And then there's a one here called X eyes and an excise is a demo program in which a pair of eyes track
指针。
the pointer.
这就是我们想要的，我们意识到实际上我们想看看这也是另一个
So that's what we want and we realize that actually we want to have a look at this is also another one
名为X man，这是一个手册页面浏览器，您知道它可能也很有用。
called X man which is a manual page browser which you know might be useful as well.
好的，现在我们非常确定要安装x11应用程序包。
OK so now we're pretty convinced we want to install the x 11 apps package.
我们怎么能做到这一点。
How can we do that.
实际上很容易做到，如果我们只在清空屏幕的时候离开，或者我们已经完成了这项工作，那么我们就可以很容易地做到这一点。
Well it's actually really easy to do if we get out of less is just when we clear the screen or we've
必须输入sudo apt get install X11应用程序，所以我们只需输入软件包的名称即可。
got to do type sudo apt get install X 11 apps so we just enter the name of the package.
现在请注意，我们正在使用apt get a Gap来安装软件包，因为我们需要我们的软件包管理器
Now notice that we're using apt get a gap to install the package because we want our package manager
从互联网获取数据，而不仅仅是从本地缓存获取数据。
to get data from the internet and not just from the local cache.
我们还传递了我们想要安装的软件包名称，嗯，因为我们想要安装X
And we also passed the package name that we wanted to install which um because we want to install X
还有iPhone应用程序，当我们按Enter键时，我们在那里输入了x11个应用程序。
and iPhone apps we typed x 11 apps in there when we press enter.
我们看到它会要求我们输入密码，然后包管理器就会继续
We see that it would ask for a password which we enter and then the package manager is going to go ahead
并安装具有许多实际需要的依赖项的新程序包。
and install the new packages with many dependencies that are actually required.
现在，如果需要大量安装，有时它可能会要求您的许可，但因为这只是安装
Now sometimes it might ask for your permission if it needs to install a lot but because its only installing
大约600千字节，就像这里一样，让我先安装一下。
about 600 kilobytes it was like Here let me just go ahead and install it.
它有一项规定，用于安装如此小的东西OK，但这与安装的软件包没有任何关系
It has a provision for something that so small OK but that has nothing to do the package is installed
现在就这么简单了。
and its as simple as that now.
X11应用程序是一个预编译包，也称为二进制包。
X 11 apps is a precompiled package also known as a binary package.
现在大多数软件包都是二进制包，这意味着制作软件的代码已经预编译
Now most packages are binary packages which means that the code that make the software has been precompiled
并预先做好准备，这样您就不必执行任何配置make和make install工作
and ready to go beforehand so you don't have to do any of that configure make and make install stuff
我们之前自己做了几个视频。
that we did a few videos ago yourself.
就像我刚从存储库安装了软件包，您就完成了。
Like I just installed the package from the repositories and you're done.
更好的是，还将跟踪软件包的更新，以便您可以在更新时更新软件包
And what's better the package will also be tracked for updates so you can update the package if new
更新可用。
updates are made available.
这真是太棒了。
How awesome is that.
现在让我们试用一下我们的新软件吧。
Now let's try out our new software.
所以我们想用xis程序。
So we wanted to use the x is program.
如果我们只播放屏幕，输入x，然后按Enter键。
So if we just play the screen and type x is in there and press enter.
你会看到，我们会在屏幕上看到这些有趣的谷歌眼睛，它们跟随着我们最周围的环境，如果
You'll see that we get these funny googly eyes pop up on the screen that follow our most surrounds if
我把最多的放在这里。
I put the most down here.
是什么吓跑了我的眼睛如果我把他弹到这里，它就会正常地跟在后面，而不是像
What was it got scared away the eyes if I pop him up here then it will follow around properly not as
虽然我想流畅地运行，但我会将其归结为我们在虚拟机中运行它。
fluidly as I'd like but I'm going to put that down to us running this in a virtual machine.
但如果你像你所知道的那样，它确实会跟得上好得多的结果。
But if like you know it does follow a whole lot nicer.
但现在这已经很酷了。
But that's pretty cool right now.
最棒的是你不会安装它的手册页
The awesome thing is the way that you wouldn't you install will come with its own man page self-disclose
这里是附加运动。
excise here.
如果我做man X Eyes，你会看到他现在实际上也安装了一个手册页面，上面写着
Then if I do man X eyes you'll see that he's actually now also got a manual page installed that says
按照鼠标X演示进行操作。
follow the mouse X demo.
而且它也有一些选择。
And it's also got some options.
您甚至可以从命令行控制消费税程序，我们在这里可以看到有一个
You can even control the excise program from the command line and we can see here that there is a there
这里有一个名为“中心”的选项，允许您为眼睛中心选择不同的颜色。
is an option here called Center which allows you to choose a different color for the center of the eyes.
例如，如果我们在中心进行附加思考，并告诉它，我认为它是两个破折号的中心
So for example if we do excise thinking at the center option and tell it I think it's two dashes center
蓝色上坡可能只有一次，也许只有一次冲刺。
blue upslope maybe just one maybe just one dash.
我们走吧。
There we go.
现在中心的冰块是蓝色的，我想让你们知道，这是当你打开
Now the center the ice is blue and I want you to know is here is the way that look when you open the
以图形化的方式制定锻炼计划。
exercise program graphically.
你不能选择改变眼睛的颜色。
You don't have the option to change the color of the eyes.
正确的。
Right.
但是在命令行中，您可以更改这一点，并且可以进行更多更改。
But from the command line you can change that and a whole lot more.
这向您强调了命令行的功能有多强大，以及它是如何为您提供更多功能的
So this is highlighting for you just how powerful the command line is and how it does give you more
比图形编辑器更强大的功能。
abilities than is possible with a graphical editor.
如果你能编辑谷歌眼睛的颜色，那么告诉我拥有一台电脑的真正意义是什么。
And if you can edit the color of googly eyes then tell me what really is the point of having a computer.
现在，S11应用程序包附带了相当多的其他软件，其中一个叫做
Now the S11 apps package came with quite a few other pieces of software inside one of which is called
你可能会觉得有用的X人。
X man which you might find useful.
现在，X man是一个用于查看手册页的图形窗口。
Now X man is a graphical window for looking at the manual pages.
如果我们在这里去掉附加作业，然后关闭它，然后输入X man，我们会在这里看到一个弹出的窗口。
So if we get rid of excise here and close it and then we type X man we'll see a window pop up over here.
现在，如果我们单击那里的手册页并打开一个大图，您就可以使用此搜索手册页
Now you can search the man pages using this if we click on manual page right there and open up a bigger
窗口，如果我们单击此处顶部的选项(如果我们按住鼠标按钮)，它将显示
window and if we click on the on the options at the top here if we hold down the mouse button it shows
按住鼠标按钮的菜单，您将看到此下拉菜单。
the menu to hold down the mouse button and you'll see this dropdown menu.
如果你继续搜索，松开鼠标，也就是说，如果我们点击搜索的东西。
Then if you go on search and let go of the mouse that is if we click the search thing.
现在我们可以在这里搜索一些东西。
And now we can search for something in here.
举个例子，如果我们看一看LS，我们试着把它看作是一个手册页，那么它就会
So this is for example if we take a look at LS and we try to look at it as a manual page then it'll
打开LS手册页面，您可以在此处浏览。
open up the LS manual page and you can browse through it here.
所以我想这是一种比你用图形化的方式看手册页更多的方式
So this is a great more I guess graphical way of taking a look at the manual pages than you do with
命令行。
the command line.
但你知道吗，我猜这只会让它看起来很漂亮，而且你还可以看看这些部分，这样你就可以
But you know which I guess it just makes it look pretty and you can also look at the sections so you
可以查看用户命令，您可以在此处看到所有用户命令。
can look in user commands and you can see all of the user commands here.
如果我想看一下，假设是地址转到行命令，或者只需单击它，它就会
And if I wanted to look at let's say the the address to line command or just click on that and it would
打开，这样就是浏览手册的一种很好的图形化方式，这样你就可以玩这个游戏了
open up so it's a nice graphical way of browsing through the manual so that's something you can play
如果你喜欢的话。
around with if you like.
我还想强调的一件事是，通过安装一个软件包，x11应用程序包实际上将
And one thing I also want to highlight is how by installing one package the x 11 apps package will actually
安装了多个不同的软件，这是非常酷的。
installed multiple different pieces of software which is super cool.
我们不需要做任何编译，我们不需要做任何配置，或者必须做的是确保
And we didn't have to do any compiling we didn't have to do any configuring or had to do was make sure
我们的软件包列表是最新的，使用sudo apt get update，然后或等待进行更新。
that our package list was up to date using sudo apt get updates and then or wait to do them whooshes
sudo apt get install，然后是程序包名，仅此而已。
sudo apt get install and then a package name and that's it.
我们可以我们可以睡觉保证我们有那个套餐的最新版本
We can we can rest assured that we've got the most up to date version of that package and it's also
此外，我们甚至不必确定软件包是否适合我们的计算机体系结构
it's also we didn't even have to find out if the package was suitable for our computers architecture
然后在你知道的386和Am 64之间做出选择，这一切都是自动迎合的，这真是太棒了。
and decide between you know 386 or am 64 that was all catered for automatically which is awesome.
但是软件包中的所有软件都是预编译的。
But all of the software in that package was pre-compiled.
那么，如果我们想要利用自由软件给予我们的自由并访问源代码呢
So what if we wanted to utilize the freedoms that free software gives us and access the source code
对于一个包，在访问存储库中的源代码时对其进行修改也是非常容易的。
for a package and modify it while accessing the source code from the repositories it's also very easy.
但是您需要做一些编辑。
But there are a few edits that you need to make.
所以对于所有的自由，天哪，我会在下一个视频中见到你。
So for all that freedom goodness I'll see you in the next video.